Roy Justus Papers
Roy Justus Papers
- Artwork
  - By Justus
    - 1964 Jan-Jun, 147 items (Oversize 34)
      Mar 5: All we need is common ordinary horse sense - eh, dobbin? (Goldwater and world revolution)
      Mar 6: I'll brow fat who bas the logic (civil rights filibuster)
      Mar 7: Grand canyon of communism
      Mar 7: Pilgrim's progress
      Mar 9: A good book to take on a trip (K reading "Virtues of Capitalism")
      Mar 10: Babe in the woods (world statesmanship and its problems)
      Mar 11: You've read that a million times (re: state sovereignty)
      Mar 12: What happened?
      Mar 13: One of the baser vermin (rats of jury tampering and court of justice)
      Mar 14: Post-mortem
      Mar 16: California, here we come (Barry and Rocky racing to GOP convention)
      Mar 17: Top hats always make good targets (anti-American incidents)
      Mar 18: Sign language (cafe Latin America)
      Mar 19: Come to full bloom in November
      Mar 20: The early bird (Goldwater candidacy for GOP nomination
      Mar 21: Exhibit A (DeGaulle holding up Red China)
      Mar 23: OK, let's get going
      Mar 24: I'm only asserting my minority rights (filibuster and civil rights bill)
      Mar 25: One school of thought on tree-pruning
      Mar 26: He's always around (public and inflation threat)
      Mar 28: Lost ball (Uncle Sam and Vietnam policy)
      Mar 29: Uncle's paper curtain (trade restriction politics)
      Mar 30: I didn't know foreign affairs could be so exciting
      Mar 31: And now the big one (filibuster cannon)
      Apr 1: I will not be an appeaser
      Apr 2: Tourist season in Latin America (old tourist revolution)
      Apr 3: McMaster (GOP lashing whip to democratic donkey cawing monkey of Bobby Baker case)
      Apr 5: A hot line that is hot (Mao and Nikita)
      Apr 6: Do you think you can make it?
      Apr 7: Here comes another one
      Apr 8: I've got a secret (DeGaulle and China and the atomic both)
      Apr 9: Leader of the free world (Uncle Sam chained to civil rights strife)
      Apr 10: Ghost over Washington (MacArthur interview)
      Apr 11: His veto (Latin American feudalist)
      Apr 13: Reckless driver (GOP and middle-of-the-road politics)
      Apr 14: Recommended reading any week
      Apr 15: If that isn't an oasis I never saw one
      Apr 16: Too many cooks (Mao and Nikita fighting over kettle)
      Apr 17: Touch of spring in the air (cold war watering plant)
      Apr 18: Not another century (negro in chasm reaching for rope of civil rights)
      Apr 20: Always a military gap (god of war screaming for more armaments)
      Apr 21: The second step (nuclear war and disarmament)
      Apr 22: We really don't need any more
      Apr 23: Whiskers to whiskers again (Castro and Uncle Sam)
      Apr 24: Peanuts for Jumbo
      Apr 25: Come, let us reason together
      Apr 27: The supreme test (LBJ and civil rights resistance)
      Apr 28: Dramatic switch in the world climate (USSR and China in the snows of cold war)
      Apr 29: The magic carpet (DeGaulle flying on top of the world)
      Apr 30: LBJ really is inhumane (LBJ lifting GOP elephant by the ears)
      May 1: Excuse the inconvenience
      May 2: May day toast (Khrushchev and Mao)
      May 4: Even the clocks are fighting (standard time vs. daylight saving time)
      May 5: Dancing on a volcano (the world on the brink of smoking Cuba)
      May 6: Superman and the presidency (Lyndon Johnson as strong man overdoing )
      May 6: Piggybacking (Barry Goldwater carrying GOP to San Francisco convention)
      May 8: Now hear this (Mao and his A bomb)
      May 9: The case of the baby dragon (USSR, and China grown up)
      May 11: Gangway! (god of war rushing missile to disarmament conference)
      May 12: Carpetbagging in the north (Governor Wallace in the primaries)
      May 13: American civil rights (USA still fighting for freedom)
      May 14: Help (re: Goldwater candidacy)
      May 15: Statesmanship (the segregationist legislator)
      May 16: Can't you hear that trumpet, Jumbo?
      May 18: Ahoy
      May 19: The filibuster (the senate tied to chair, in dripping water)
      May 20: Try this for size
      May 21: Hazardous firewarden (atomic frightfulness and brush fire wars)
      May 22: Agonizing reappraisal (Uncle Sam sinking in mire of southeast Asia)
      May 23: Correction
      May 25: Into the fray
      May 26: Eating crow (Barry and foolhardy statements)
      May 28: Staunch supporter
      May 29: That's easy
      May 30: There may be gold beyond those hills (dark horse approaching California GOP primary)
      Jun 1: Soaring, soaring (the vulture H bomb over the troubled world)
      Jun 2: I know how they feel in Washington
      Jun 3: The volunteer (election politics and the southeast Asia policy)
      Jun 4: Branded? (Barry branding GOP elephant with "Au H2O")
      Jun 5: Why not victory?!
      Jun 6: Fair weather or stork? (USA and USSR in the joint weather satellite program)
      Jun 8: All aboard who's coming aboard (Goldwater's ark)
      Jun 10: The iceman cometh
      Jun 11: Forecast: hot and windy
      Jun 16: Elephant and mouse (responsible Republicanism and Goldwater absurdities)
      Jun 17: The path has always been hazardous (freedom of expression along the path of human rights)
      Jun 18: The solutions are all so simple (Goldwater and his crystal ball)
      Jun 19: And now the summit (Uncle Sam climbing the peaks of civil rights legislation)
      Jun 20: No torch of liberty (civil rights and violence)
      Jun 22: I can't get this free speech bunk (K and U.S. elections)
      Jun 23: I will not budge
      Jun 24: I smell something and it isn't good (China and Uncle Sam)
      Jun 26: (no caption) (three men peeking through key-holes)
      Jun 27: Barry certainly stirred up the hornets
      Jun 29: You back again? (Berlin looking in at the world)
      Jun 30: Visitor (democratic donkey bringing flowers to GOP sick with Goldwateritis)
    - 1964 Jul-Dec, 141 items (Oversize 35)
      Jul 1: The lecture (racism pointing his club at white supremacy)
      Jul 2: Down for the second time?
      Jul 3: Battle of Gettysburg (Ike and battered modern Republicanism)
      Jul 4: Independence Day (arm of negro holding up American flag)
      Jul 6: Which comes first? (GOP candidate or platform?)
      Jul 7: What this country needs is a big ice pack
      Jul 8: Platform builders (GOP factionalism)
      Jul 9: Road sign in San Francisco
      Jul 13: Oh I can wear any size or color (Barry and platform committee)
      Jul 14: Right in broad daylight (Barry running away with GOP party organization and platform)
      Jul 15: The real thing or a hoax? (GOP platform statement on atomic bomb policy)
      Jul 16: It's new all right - what is it? (new republican party)
      Jul 17: Out of the ashes (civil rights strife, GOP convention)
      Jul 18: The thinker (GOP elephant rank and file battered and bruised)
      Jul 20: I expect each one of you fifty sovereign states to do your duty (Barry on his mount of crusade against world communism)
      Jul 21: Picture of a computer in action
      Jul 22: This is not moderation (KKK about to burn the cross of civil rights)
      Jul 23: The global interest is completely natural
      Jul 24: Victim of extremism (race riots and Uncle Sam's battered image)
      Jul 25: They've never looked so big and juicy (GOP and the solid south)
      Jul 27: Gosh! That's never match the cow palace (LBJ ringing the bell of nomination for v.p.)
      Jul 28: To a united Europe (DeGaulle drinking a toast to mirrored image)
      Jul 29: Mary, Mary, how your garden does grow
      Jul 30: Extremism in the east
      Jul 31: You still here? (conservatives and liberals riding GOP elephant)
      Aug 1: Shucks - this is easier
      Aug 3: Among the photos or the moon
      Aug 4: Something we can do without (political slander stirring up tar)
      Aug 5: That? Oh, that's extremism after it's been defined
      Aug 6: How long the fuse? (N Vietnam and U.S. military clash)
      Aug 7: Crises always excite him (S.E. Asia and the H-bomb)
      Aug 9: O.k. but do be careful
      Aug 10: The greatest show on earth
      Aug 11: Chief casualty in US air strike (Mao and the "US is a paper tiger" doctrine)
      Aug 12: Barry explains the meaning of extremism
      Aug 13: Uncle is getting himself a new pair of boots (Uncle Sam carrying scroll of the anti-poverty act, his shoes worn out)
      Aug 14: Isn't this rather extreme?
      Aug 15: Atlantic City spectacle
      Aug 17: The white backlash isn't very noisy
      Aug 18: The old gray mare (rural America and reapportionment)
      Aug 19: Super segregationist (Mao chopping the world into halves - white and colored)
      Aug 20: Barry goes a-courtin'
      Aug 21: The heat in the kitchen (LBJ stirring up his kettles of problems)
      Aug 22: One thing in common
      Aug 24: Chief attraction
      Aug 25: Ornery critter (LBJ, the Democratic south, and civil rights issue)
      Aug 26: Defining and disposing of extremism
      Aug 27: Paul Bunyan meets another giant (Humphrey at Atlantic City)
      Aug 28: Twentieth century lecture (U.S. foreign policy plank)
      Aug 29: Come, let us reason together (LBJ and GOP moderates)
      Aug 31: After all, he does have an interest
      Sep 1: Oh no (election campaigns running down the voter)
      Sep 2: Fear of high places? (LBJ and the polls)
      Sep 3: Don't you want to fight for your freedom? (Uncle Sam with rifle, and the fisherman, S. Vietnam politicians)
      Sep 4: The first reader - and the last (we must never have an atomic war)
      Sep 5: Vacation time for congress
      Sep 8: The inimitable Barry
      Sep 9: Leaving home (republican and democratic party defectors)
      Sep 10: Revisionist art? (K changing signs to read Mao go home)
      Sep 11: Here comes Dora II (the fury of politics)
      Sep 13: Cautious Sam
      Sep 14: The thriller
      Sep 15: Op come this is extremely frustrating (the inevitably changing world)
      Sep 16: Crow seems to be his dish (Barry and Miller)
      Sep 17: I already have a suicide weapon
      Sep 18: The ogre (man in laboratory producing death masked "War of extermination")
      Sep 19: Busy beekeeper (K and world communism)
      Sep 21: Political sirens
      Sep 22: Political images are important everywhere (DeGaulle hovering over south America)
      Sep 23: The lamentations of Jeremiah
      Sep 24: The trials of our public servants
      Sep 25: King Canute (reactionary forces sweeping back waves of intellectualism)
      Sep 26: You supply the funds - I'll supply the leadership (De Gaulle and alliance for progress in South America)
      Sep 28: On the campaign issues
      Sep 29: Barry had a little lamb (BG and his convention "Extremist" statement)
      Sep 30: I'm so bored and frustrated - let's set it off just for the heck of it (two monkeys and the H bomb on the world)
      Oct 1: That old tar brush again
      Oct 2: Easier to read and more exciting too
      Oct 3: I have complete confidence of a smashing victory (Democratic donkey and GOP elephant in foot race)
      Oct 5: Waiting for Hilda (the world peering for the hurricane of China's A-bomb)
      Oct 6: How'd I ever get up here? (Barry on the nuclear control cloud)
      Oct 7: Melancholy days (voter buried under speeches, leaves falling from political tree)
      Oct 8: Is everybody listening?
      Oct 9: The wrecking crew (liars and scandalmongers chopping down pillar of America's democratic institutions)
      Oct 10: The home stretch
      Oct 12: The choice (LBJ and HHH driving car of responsible leadership on road to 21st century)
      Oct 13: A free people's best guardian (free press)
      Oct 14: We could lose 500 million people and still survive (Mao and the A bomb)
      Oct 15: The echo
      Oct 16: Mushroom cloud changes shape (Khrushchev's ouster)
      Oct 17: Now I am ready(China's Mao holding A-bomb and summit meeting proposal)
      Oct 19: Hello, there (USSR bear booting out K's China dragon with A bomb appearing in horizon)
      Oct 20: Trick kaleidoscope (political campaign smut)
      Oct 21: Desperate assault (Barry tarring LBJ's poll head with moral charges)
      Oct 22: Let's not let this one get lost
      Oct 23: Sad trail of a campaign wagon (smut and abandoned campaign)
      Oct 24: A call to her straying cubs (Russian bear on communist summit)
      Oct 25: We just started with one small 'conventional' atom bomb (the world blown to bits)
      Oct 28: New member (China, with bomb, entering Atomic Bombs for Peace Club)
      Oct 29: To the rescue
      Oct 30: Where I stand (Barry standing on his head)
      Oct 31: Trying to drag him into the 20th century (moderate republicans tugging at Goldwater faction)
      Nov 2: Voters of America will decide (president of U.S. under burden of the globe of destiny of the free world)
      Nov 3: Man of the year (long-suffering voter)
      Nov 4: One price of freedom (Uncle Sam sweeping up election debris)
      Nov 5: Mandate
      Nov 6: Viewing the wreck (Barry's smashed oxcart)
      Nov 7: And then the ranch on the Potomac (LBJ and HHH facing the ram of duties of office)
      Nov 9: New repairman (Brezhnev with glue pot and tape to mend the fallen Humpty Dumpty of communist dogma)
      Nov 11: Bubble gum (western alliance and De Gaulle blowing up "The glory of France")
      Nov 12: At the bottom of it all
      Nov 13: Lover's leap (the bomb rushing civilization to the chasm of oblivion)
      Nov 16: Traffic victim (disarmament efforts trodden down by arms race)
      Nov 17: And winter isn't too far away (GOP elephant after election, shivering on the doorstep)
      Nov 18: Who will control the monster? (nuclear arms)
      Nov 19: More stubborn than usual (national interest and election bitterness)
      Nov 20: The thinker
      Nov 21: And you think you've got troubles
      Nov 23: Crosscurrents (nationalism and world alliances)
      Nov 24: Nostalgia strikes Europe, too (De Gaulle and his dream of knighthood and castles)
      Nov 25: Crowbar (China trying to open door of A-bomb)
      Nov 26: Darkest (vulture over Africa)
      Nov 27: America's two-party system
      Nov 28: Ouch (U.S. Military cutbacks and local economies)
      Nov 30: Exercise in futility (LBJ proclaiming world peace)
      Dec 1: Beginning to get the hang of it (Russian bear on bicycle of capitalist incentives)
      Dec 2: Tis the season (worn out Christmas stocking hung on U.N.)
      Dec 3: Rather an awkward position (Uncle Sam trying to crack the Vietnam nut)
      Dec 4: The man on horseback (De Gaulle riding "French nuclear Power")
      Dec 5: Spelling it out for him (Minnesota legislature reapportionment)
      Dec 7: Contemplating his chains (GOP elephant chained to ultra-conservativism)
      Dec 8: Planning the itinerary(Santa Claus with his pack of peace on earth)
      Dec 9: His behavioral pattern has been altered (bad boy world and the policemen of atomic horror)
      Dec 10: The many horns of a dilemma (Uncle Sam and Vietnam)
      Dec 11: Window-shopping (GOP looking at candy cane of party unity)
      Dec 12: All for world peace
      Dec 14: The inevitability of change (NATO and shifting sands of world politics)
      Dec 15: Trying for a record? (traffic deaths in Minneapolis )
      Dec 16: Living dangerously has its penalties (GOP sick from smoking ultra-right experiment)
      Dec 29: Ho ho ho! (the bomb as Santa Claus with his pack of world peace)
      Dec 30: The spirited ritur (man in racing auto toasting happy new year.)
    - 1965 Jan-Jun, 131 items (Oversize 36)
      Jan 1: Listen, young fella
      Jan 2: And I resolve to work for peace in the new year (spread of nuclear weapons)
      Jan 6: Getting off dead center with a bang (the public and the LBJ program)
      Jan 7: Master segregationist (China holding up united nations of the colored races)
      Jan 8: In it but not of it (De Gaulle and the western alliance)
      Jan 9: A wagon and a star (LBJ hooking congress onto star of the great society)
      Jan 12: Sissies! (death smoking a cigarette)
      Jan 13: Can you spare a dime for world peace? (girl in rags - U.N. - begging with cup)
      Jan 14: Bliss-ful elephant (GOP)
      Jan 15: Persistent pussy (Minnesota legislature and sales tax)
      Jan 16: Here we go again!
      Jan 18: The center seems so popular - now
      Jan 19: No place for hobnails (world diplomacy amid a bombs)
      Jan 20: The splitting headache (the sick world - resurgence of nationalism)
      Jan 21: Morning after (LBJ and the stock pile of the president's job)
      Jan 22: Longest siesta on record (Uncle Sam carrying load of the alliance for progress alone, as Latin America sleeps)
      Jan 26: Winston Churchill (keeper of Human Freedom memorial wreath)
      Jan 27: Jammed (GOP out hunting rabbit, the great society)
      Jan 28: Language barrier
      Jan 29: Gold rush competition is keen (federal, state, and local claims on tax monies )
      Jan 30: Do-it-yourself fit (chine and erector toy - build your own united nations)
      Feb 1: Big man on campus (education treading the world)
      Feb 2: Walls of Jericho (nationalism blowing trumpet at U.N.)
      Feb 3: The challengers (Russian bear end Chinese dragon on summit of world communism)
      Feb 4: The sower (Sukarno sowing dragon's teeth in southeast Asia)
      Feb 5: The wax job (GOP and harmony polish)
      Feb 6: But you're not solving my problems (the sociologist and the computer)
      Feb 8: The juggernaut (mechanization and the family farmer)
      Feb 9: Why not turn that job over to me? (atomic war and world population control)
      Feb 10: Sometimes it's hard to smile (brickbats for Uncle Sam and his world leadership)
      Feb 11: This could be my cue (atomic holocaust and faltering U.N.)
      Feb 12: Prelude to victory? (Vietnam blowing up the world?)
      Mar 1: There ariseth a little cloud out of the sea, like a man's hand (the China problem)
      Mar 2: Closer than you think (doomsday is close at hand and the bomb)
      Mar 3: Man waiting for a shave
      Mar 4: Beginning to feel his oats
      Mar 5: Could smash that up in a hurry (atomic horror and Vietnam stalemate)
      Mar 6: Change of posture in Vietnam
      Mar 8: Boy at the dike
      Mar 9: Kaleidoscope (U.S. Public and Vietnam situation)
      Mar 10: Hoping for the worst (the vulture of foes of the U.N.)
      Mar 11: The missionary (Uncle Sam, tattered and torn with civil rights violations)
      Mar 12: Real estate problem (traditional nationalism painting the world in sections)
      Mar 13: There are people like that (China screaming I don't wanta co-exist)
      Mar 16: Among the victims (the racist beating up U.S. Constitution)
      Mar 17: It's not all honey (Russian bear and world communism)
      Mar 18: The boiling pot
      Mar 19: Gravedigger (De Gaulle digging up NATO)
      Mar 20: Another milestone (man in space)
      Mar 22: Literacy test (Governor Wallace and federal authority)
      Mar 23: Good-neighbor hysteria
      Mar 24: Snow - beautiful snow
      Mar 25: Might be intelligent life down there
      Mar 26: Nonlethal gas at home, too (public and air pollution)
      Mar 27: Versatile Charles (Mao signing treaty with De Gaulle)
      Mar 29: Theater of seasons (sitting out the snowstorm)
      Mar 30: You'd like to see the president? He'd probably like to see you, too (KKK at white house)
      Mar 31: O for the touch of a vanish'd hand
      Apr 1: What a wonderful invention (the bomb and the Vietnam escalator)
      Apr 2: First we've got to do something to improve your image (chairmen bliss and sick GOP elephant)
      Apr 3: You ain't seen nothin' yet
      Apr 5: Captive nations in revolt (Sioux Indians)
      Apr 6: What are they really saying?
      Apr 7: Satellite ducklings (mother hen of communism with ducklings swimming away)
      Apr 8: How do you let go? (Uncle Sam holding tail of Vietnam dragon)
      Apr 9: Ajar
      Apr 10: His just dues (ol' man winter drowning in floods)
      Apr 12: First comes the wrecker (De Gaulle and the western alliance)
      Apr 13: Every so often I need to remind you
      Apr 14: Wormy apple (traditional nationalism burrowing through the world)
      Apr 15: Skateboard (Uncle Sam on skateboard of Vietnam)
      Apr 16: Hard to concentrate (public and spring floods)
      Apr 19: Not all weapons are modem (the caveman-destroy the u. N. Forces)
      Apr 20: Aerial combat over Washington (the hawks and the doves over the capitol)
      Apr 21: The boys stood on the burning deck (Mao and Uncle Sam on ship Vietnam)
      Apr 22: Hope springs eternal
      Apr 23: Left standing in the debris (the need for flood control)
      Apr 24: Why the job is slow (legislators wooing iamb off tree of reapportionment)
      Apr 26: Here we go again (impeach Earl Warren and Prof. Sibley)
      Apr 27: Heads I win - tails you lose (Mao flipping coin with Uncle Sam over Vietnam)
      Apr 28: But, Bob - everybody knows we've got that (John Q., to McNamara with bomb)
      Apr 29: The better part of valor
      Apr 30: A tough job sifting them out (U.S. sifting out phony revolutions from genuine revolutions)
      May 1: My family can take punishment (the world and its catastrophes)
      May 3: May flower (world peace amid the weeds)
      May 4: Come let us reason together (revolutionaries at gunpoint of LBJ)
      May 5: The great debate (collective security of U.N. vs. big power diplomacy)
      May 6: And now what'll we talk about?!
      May 7: Strain on the fire department (U.S.A. fire department and the world aflame)
      May 8: Nature and man against man (hurricane and nuclear bomb clouds)
      May 10: Could this be our Uncle Sam?
      Jun 15: The contest (De Gaulle racing Father Time)
      Jun 16: It is my considered opinion there'll be no need to draft you (atomic destruction of civilization)
      Jun 17: One world - and what a world (Uncle Sam policeman of the world)
      Jun 17: Riot's greatest devastation (citizenship responsibility)
      Jun 18: The outcast (China and U.N. arms talk)
      Jun 19: Far above the jungles (Russian bear on tightrope above Vietnam)
      Jun 21: The guard (GOP free society association, guarding the grave of super-conservatism)
      Jun 22: The torment (Uncle Sam tied at column, as drops of Vietnam water fall upon him)
      Jun 23: Thriving on it (world communism eating on grounds of overpopulation, poverty, and ignorance)
      Jun 24: What do you intend to do with that? (the world and the dragon of China's nuclear potential)
      Jun 25: Still the chief burden (U.N. and big power politics)
      Jun 26: Caution (third party cigarettes)
      Jun 28: The throwback (the beast of resurgence of nationalism and the a bomb)
      Jun 29: Ny watermelon patch
      Jun 30: The color line (U.S.S.R and China, the latter painting the Afro-Asian policy)
    - 1965 Jul-Dec, 138 items (Oversize 37)
      Jul 1: I'm hungry
      Jul 2: Rah-rah-rah, we want a touchdown
      Jul 3: To think I was born of revolution
      Jul 5: And we've had automation ever since (cavemen: we'll call it the wheel)
      Jul 6: We still have our independence (wrecked autos and survivor)
      Jul 8: New model at the airport (Mac - book censorship - flying over airport)
      Jul 9: I think you're beginning to look quite respectable (world military and atomic horror)
      Jul 10: The two-party system (GOP elephant and democratic donkey in embrace as rocks of faction and splinter are hurled at them)
      Jul 12: Asian tom-tom (China beating the drum of Asia and Africa for the colored people)
      Jul 13: Twins
      Jul 14: Let us reason together